CALVIN BROWNLEE

71 4th Avenue, Brooklyn, NY, 11217 646-637-7467, calvinbrownlee@gmail.com

Portfolio Site LinkedIn Profile Github Profile

SUMMARY

I am a Full-Stack Web Developer and Designer with 6 years of experience in the fast-paced tech industry as a Production Manager and Quality Engineer. I turn creative design solutions into reality, continuously improve myself, and make a positive impact with my work.

PROJECTS

Museum Catalog App (http://www.catalog.calvinbrownlee.com/)

February 2018

- A RESTful web app designed using Flask framework, JSON, and a SQL database for the back-end.
- OAuth2 provides authentication for CRUD functionality via Google and Facebook accounts.
- The application is hosted on a LAMP server using Amazon Lightsail Ubuntu Server, Apache, PostgreSQL, and Python.

Local Map Project (http://www.map.calvinbrownlee.com/)

January 2018

- A front-end website built with Google Maps Javascript and Wikipedia API integration to populate a map with relevant details including Wikipedia articles.
- Knockout.js framework used to implement MVVM.

Portfolio Website (http://www.calvinbrownlee.com/)

December 2017

- Portfolio website designed using HTML/CSS and JQuery that displays completed projects and contact information.
- Responsive mobile first design and SEO optimized.

EXPERIENCE

Quality Engineer, Bond

New York, NY — January 2017 - November 2017

- Solved quality and efficiency shortfalls through data insights by collaborating across product department teams and
 engineering new operations processes resulting in an increased output by 12%, machine efficiency by 15%, and
 FPY by 22%; reduced operational costs by \$600,000 over a one-year period.
- Negotiated with suppliers on quality standards and formalized a refund structure for substandard work; recuperated
 \$15,000 over a one-year period.
- Created and defined quality and documentation standards. Worked with production team to build and implement.
- Collaborated with Product team on new product features.

Production and Repair Service Manager, Makerbot

Brooklyn, NY — February 2013 - October 2016

- Shaped and directly supervised the production department comprised of over 120 assembly line workers, repair technicians, and line leaders.
- Independently developed assembly work documents, training standards, attendance system, and hiring practices.

Machinist, Caterpillar

Oxford, MS — June 2010 - June 2012

- Operated and calibrated CNC lathes and mills.
- Trained employees on operation of CNC lathes and mills.

SKILLS

Programming Languages

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python

Library/Frameworks

JQuery, Flask, Knockout.js, Node.js, Bootstrap

Other Hard Skills

LAMP Server Administration, UX and UI Design, Amazon Web Services, Git, Github, PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy

Soft Skills

Organized, Fast Learner, Communication Skills, Self Starter, Problem Solving, Teamwork, Detail Oriented

EDUCATION

Udacity Nanodegree Program

Full-Stack Developer — 2017 - 2018

University of Mississippi

Psychology — 2006 - 2008 (100+ course hours completed)

Jones County Junior College

Associate's Degree, General Studies — 2004 - 2006